#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/phinguyen11 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Usability Testing
User Interface Design
Wireframing

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)

### Honors-Awards

Second Place Award for Best Project Best in Genre - Design

# Phi Nguyen

Senior UX/UI Designer at Vinamilk

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Summary

I am an UX/UI designer who specialized in creating beautiful, yet functional digital interfaces for mobile apps and websites. My passions are designing to solve people's problems and making them satisfy with my products. I love what I do, and I never stop learning from negative feedback to improve my design skills.

## Experience

Vinamilk Senior UX/UI Designer July 2023 - Present (1 year 9 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

### Übank

Senior UX/UI Designer June 2021 - July 2023 (2 years 2 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Created interaction strategies that helped, developing navigation and flow, designed wireframes and interactive prototype, organized content, and advocated for the needs and goals of real users by doing usability tests and observation researches.
- Conceived, planned and led some main design projects such as: Registration revamp, Term deposit feature, Digital Card, and new Loan application process. Especially by enhancing registration flow, the company is able to acquire a massive amount of users (from 80K to nearly 300k) within 3 months.
- Spearheaded communication with UX Director, Data Analysis Director,
   Product Owner, Project Manager, and Development Managers to successfully complete every design of both Übank app and FE Online app.

Vietnam International Bank (VIB) - Ngân Hàng Quốc Tế Digital UX/UI Specialist July 2020 - June 2021 (1 year) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Translated Product Owner ideas (based on existing system) into functional requirements, wireframes, prototypes, and interactive mockups within prescribed deadlines.
- Implemented the latest design innovations to ensure that the product is in accordance with the cutting-edge technology.
- Conducted research and optimized existing user interface design while testing for intuitively and experience.
- Played a big role in defining the design system of MyVIB 2.0 and inserting a very first brick into the UX structure of this new banking app.

InApps Technology
UX/UI Designer
June 2018 - July 2020 (2 years 2 months)
Vietnam

- Worked closely with the Project Coordinator, the Development Team to propose new solutions to complex user-centered design problems
- Created compelling user interfaces and contributed to the development process to ensure a consistent and intuitive user experience across multiple platforms - with the highest standards of aesthetics
- Translated Product Owner ideas (based on existing system) into functional requirements, wireframes, prototypes and interactive mockups within prescribed deadlines.
- Defined clear application workflow and specific screens for development team
- Worked closely with Development team to ensure functionality is implemented as per wireframes, mockups and design documents
- Played as team leader to conduct review activity for other designers' work

SaigonTech | SAIGON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Graphic Designer March 2018 - May 2018 (3 months)

Vietnam

- Provided proposal layouts and designs under extremely tight deadlines.
- Developed and maintained print/web collateral, graphical standards, marketing.
- Worked in conjunction with the Art Director in creating integrated marketing.

Walgreens
Customer Service Associate
July 2017 - December 2017 (6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Provided customers with courteous, friendly, fast, and efficient service.
- Provided customer service in the photo area, including digital passport photo service, poster print and creative machine, suggestive sell of promotional photo products.

Weber Shandwick Creative Design Intern March 2017 - June 2017 (4 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Clients: Amazon, Envestnet, Evolve, Exelixis, Genentech, Redbull, Seagate,
   Sutter Health, and VMware.
- Designed Decks using Google Slide and Power Point for clients' pitch, as well as internal and external presentations base on the brand/ style guidelines.
- Created, updated, and refined multiple graphic design works for both print and digital, including posters, postcards, banners, leave-behinds, and web designs, and social media platform such Facebook's canvas.
- Collaborated and worked closely with Associate Creative Director, Art Director, Studio Manager, and Copywriter on various clients' projects -Seagate's Facebook Canvas, Exelixis's website, VMware's postcard, etc.

San Francisco State University
1 year 6 months

UX Student Designer at Information Technology Services (ITS) August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Designed print, digital display banner for advertising the San Francisco State University Mobile App.
- Helped increasing the numbers of App downloading by 200% within 2 months.
- Developed and executed final poster, ITS website, and personas through 100 campus-wide student interviews.
- Collaborated with product managers, Drupal team, and senior designers to explore multiple UX solutions via A/B testing.

Coordinator of Office of Faculty Affair July 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 2 months) San Francisco Bay Area

- Supported and collaborated with the office's supervisor.
- Managed room reservation and answered phone call.
- Managed Faculty Affair's website and re-designed Faculty Manual.

Freelance / Graphic Design, Brand Development, Web Design and UI Design

Freelance Graphic Designer
July 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Femresources Leaflet Design, 2017
- Northern California Cherry Blossom Festival, 2016.
- Partners in School Innovation Decal design, 2015.
- Bella Donna Nail Salon Business card design, 2014.

City College of San Francisco Coordinator of Office of Instruction August 2010 - December 2013 (3 years 5 months) San Francisco Bay Area

- Helped and supported more than 50 evening instructors.
- Delivered mail, photo copied, and provided supplies.
- Created and managed class's schedules for upcoming semester.

## Education

San Francisco State University
Bachelor's Degree, Visual Communication Design · (2014 - 2016)

City College of San Francisco
Associate's Degree, Art and Humanities · (2010 - 2013)